准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
珊瑚营怪客  下集
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
听好  我想说的是
Look, all I'm saying
在恐怖中生存可是有规矩的
is there are rules to surviving horror
就比如  不能单独离开
Like, don't go off alone
不能说  我马上回来
don't say "I'll be right back,"
不能亲亲抱抱
and no canoodling
更不能瞎扯淡
And don't be ridiculous
你们表现得也太幼稚了
You're all acting like a bunch of babies
我才不怕什么生物
I'm not afraid of any creature
或者斧头杀人魔什么的
or axe murderer or whatever
真要有什么可怕玩意冲我来
If anything scary came at me
我就这样打他  再那样打他
I'd hit him like this, and I'd hit him like that
太好笑了  凯伦
Very funny, Karen
太好笑了
Very funny
走了  爱搞笑的
Come on, Chuckles
离开这个儿童烧烤野餐会
Let's blow this weenie roast
一起亲亲抱抱
and "canoodle"
我要是你  就不会那么做
I wouldn't do that if I were you
我的事你都做不来  怪东西
You wouldn't do anything I would do, weirdo
烤棉花糖饼
S'mores
你知道那是松果吧
You know that's a pinecone, right?
松果可以给我多来点
S'more pinecone for me
[ s'more（烤棉花糖饼）
与 that's more（有更多）谐音 ]
辣辣的小恶魔
Spicy little devil
还是讲点故事吧
Maybe we should tell stories
省得老是去想黑暗中潜伏的鬼影
to keep our minds off
the terrifying horror that lurks in the dark
我先讲
I'll start
从前有一个夜晚  就跟今晚一样
It was a night just like tonight
在一座废弃老营地  就跟这里一样
in an old abandoned camp just like this one
有着这么一个家伙
But there was something out there
在林中四处潜行  十分恐怖
something spooky that prowled in the woods
你认真的吗
Seriously?
要讲露营鬼故事
A scary camping story?
我现在就只记得这个故事
It's the only story I can remember right now
快讲血腥斧头杀人魔那段情节吧
Tell the part with all the bloody axe-murdering
不行
No
差不多行了
All right, that's it
别围着营火了
No more campfire
一定要团结在一起
We're all gonna stay together
到从前住过的小船小屋过夜
in the old Dinghy Cabin until morning
好办法
Good idea
我去找痞老板跟凯伦
I'll go get Plankton and Karen
我马上回来
I'll be right back
她死定了
She's dead
我们从前住过的小屋
Our old cabin
感觉是间危房
It's a fixer-upper
拆房还差不多
More like a tearer-downer
我要睡上铺
I call top bunk
海绵宝宝  好像已经有谁
SpongeBob, I think there's someone
睡在床上了
sleeping in this bunk bed
我能昏倒了吗
Can I faint now?
请便
Be my guest
得拿这位怎么办
What do I do with this?
好耶
Yes
我上一垒了
I made it to first base
[ 一垒：棒球术语，也指男女亲亲抱抱 ]
找到你们了
There you are
你们好
Hello
你什么毛病啊
What is wrong with you?
我差点就心脏病发了
I almost had a heart attack
干嘛戴面具
What's with the mask?
别那么夸张
Don't be so dramatic
我只是在林中找到了从前的冰球器材
I just found
some of my old hockey equipment in the woods
我的名字还写在上面
It's still got my name on it
往日时光真美好
Good times
痞老板
Plankton?
凯伦
Karen?
我知道你们只是想吓我
Come on, I know you're just trying to scare me
我的老冰车啊
Holy Zamboni
我刚刚讲到哪来着了
All right, so where was I?
对了  想起来了
Oh, yeah, I remember now
有这么一个可怕的家伙
There was something spooky out there
在林中四处潜行
prowling around in the woods
发出了可怕的尖叫声
and it made a terrifying shriek
辅导员  勿入
我没心情再怕下去了
I'm tired of being scared
我也是
Me too
我还有心情怕下去
I'm not tired of being scared yet
大家快来  是时候反击了
Come on, fellers, it's time we fought back
是  怪怪怪客
The C-C-C-Creeper
章鱼哥
Squidward?
派大星
Patrick
起码章鱼哥平安无事
At least Squidward's safe
是你们
You guys?
你们几个白痴来干什么
What are you idiots doing here?
我们是来开珊瑚营地团圆会的
We're here for the Kamp Koral reunion
你也是吗
Aren't you?
团圆会
Reunion?
才不是  我已经待这里一周了
No, I've been here for a week
自从我被禁止
ever since I was banned
在裤头村吹竖笛就这样了
from playing clarinet in Bikini Bottom
城市最近确实比较宁静了些
The city has been rather peaceful lately
你就没发现
Didn't you notice
我已经整整一周没去上班了吗
that I haven't been at work for a whole week?
我都当你是在上厕所
I assumed you were just on a bathroom break
你肯定有收到邀请吧
You must have gotten an invite
等一下
Hold on
这封应该是你的
I believe this is yours
这封信是寄给助步器老头的
This letter is for Old Man Walker
压根就没参加过这夏令营
He never even went to this camp
好一个胜地全让你们白痴毁了
You idiots ruined my perfect getaway
这下只好再次逃离了
Now I have to get away again--
从头再来
all over again
果不其然
Typical
不要  别走
No, wait
别单独出去啊
Don't go out alone
章鱼哥
Squidward
太迟了
It's too late
他消失了
He's vanished
大家全都消失了
Everybody's vanished
全都消失了
Everybody?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
救命  我要消失了
Help, I'm vanishing
加把劲  派大星
Come on, Patrick
显形啊
materialize
没事吧  兄弟
Are you OK, buddy?
不知道
I don't know
我还在使劲思考
I'm still processing
章鱼哥之所以会被拿下
Squidward was taken
是因为他违反了恐怖规矩
because he ignored the rules of horror
意思是说不能劳动节过后穿白衣吗
You mean, don't wear white after Labor Day?
[ 白衣只在夏季穿
美国劳动节为九月第一个周一 ]
再重复一遍  不能单独离开
I repeat, don't go off alone
不能说  我马上回来
don't say "I'll be right back,"
绝对不能亲亲抱抱
and absolutely no canoodling
看我证明
Watch, I'll prove it
我的宝贝小南瓜
My pumpkin
我的宝贝小糖块
My little lump of sugar
甜心蜜糖派
Sweet honey pie
他刚说蜜糖派吗
Did he say "honey pie"?
我饿了
I'm hungry
所以才不能亲亲抱抱
And that's why you don't canoodle
大家退后
Stand back, y'all
不管是谁  都有可能还在接近我们
Whoever it is, they're probably still close
一起逮到他
Let's get ‘em
肯定还有地方能让我安心吹竖笛
There must be somewhere I can play
不会突然冒出个谁来烦我
without any annoying interruptions
你们几个傻子最好别来跟踪我
You imbeciles better not be following me
那些白痴害我心惊肉跳的
Those morons got me all jumpy
不得不承认  真的很可爱
I hate to admit it, but that's pretty cute
当我没说
I take it back
坏兔子
Bad bunnies
到底是谁在搞鬼
All right, who is it now?
我手上有竖笛  而且我还敢吹它
I have a clarinet, and I'm not afraid to use it
看来把他们吹跑了
Guess I blew them away
章鱼哥
Squidward?
哈维
Harvey?
泡芙老师
Mrs. Puff?
阿莫
Mo?
上流小姐
Lady Upturn?
老爸
Daddy?
我在大喊
I'm hollering
我在大叫
I'm yelling
你们听见没
Do you hear that?
有竖笛声
Clarinet music
一定是章鱼哥
It must be Squidward
原来是只蜗牛
It's just a snail
怪不得好听到不像章鱼哥
Yeah, I thought it sounded too good
先保管好
I'll keep this safe
找到章鱼哥就还回去
until we can give it back to Squidward
好
Yeah
他应该不敢把竖笛要回来了吧
I doubt he'll want it back now
我累死了
I'm beat
还是等明天再去找大伙儿吧
I think we should call off the search until morning
各位
Guys
我被抓到了
It got me
救命
Help
她消失了
She's gone
怪客抓走她了
The Creeper's got her
现在还抓走派大星了
Now it's got Patrick
声音是那边传来的
It's coming from back there
从前的拖网渔船小屋
The old Trawler cabin
派大星
Patrick?
什么事
What is up?
刚刚是你在叫吗
Was that you yelling?
叫
Yelling?
对对对
Oh, yeah, yeah
我是想警告你们有
I wanted to warn you about, um
这个蜘蛛网
This spiderweb?
对
Yeah
谢了  兄弟
Thanks, buddy
听我数到三
On the count of three, boys--
一
one
二
two
三
three
从前吓到尖叫的那些人当中
Of all the screamers back in the day
就数你们最棒了
you guys were the best
大小萝丝
Big and Lil Roxie?
还是小大萝丝
Or is it Little and Big Roxie?
你们换位置了
Y'all switched places?
月相每变换三次都会这样
It happens every three moon cycles
轮换大小可公平了
Turnabout is fair play
大家晚上好
Good evening, everyone
欢迎光临我的小屋
Welcome to my parlor
剪剪剪
Snip, snip, snip
你好啊  普芮达楚伊
Howdy, Preda Tory
基德法拉图  你长大了
Kidferatu, all grown up
真高兴能看见你死得好好的
Good to see you're still dead and well
他现在是伯爵了
He's a count now
真高兴能再见到你们
It's great to see you guys again
水滴鱼吉米
Jimmy Blobfish?
你样子
You look--
对  我都知道
Yeah, I know, I know
我毁容了
I lost my looks
小时候我可爱多了
I was much cuter when I was younger
内在美才是真的美
It's the delicious insides that count
是没错  但他的外在也很美味啊
Yeah, but his outside isn't so bad either
他的味道还是很像枫糖浆
He still tastes like maple syrup
差点忘了
I almost forgot
我们有危险了
We're all in danger
珊瑚营地里有怪客
There's a creeper in camp
怪客
A creeper?
感觉跟我们可像了
Sounds like our kind of people
你们不懂
Y'all don't understand
来参加团圆会的全被他抓走了
He's been snatching up everyone
who's here for the reunion
怪客听起来好迷人
This Creeper sounds fascinating
怎么做才能让他来抓我们
What do we gotta do to get snatched?
哈维说要随便违反一条恐怖规矩
Well, Harvey said you have to break
one of the rules of horror
那就简单了
That's easy
我们了如指掌
We know ‘em all
你们干嘛
What are you doing?
我们马上回来
We'll be right back
他们消失了
They're gone
有了
I got it
我知道怪客是谁了
I know who the Creeper is
想想看
Think about it
谁从前老是搞恶作剧整我们
Who used to prank us all the time?
我们从前的山民朋友  娜琳跟诺比
Our old hill folk friends, Narlene and Nobby
所以现在是时候给他们整回去了
So I say it's time for us to prank them back
娜琳的小屋看着像是废弃了
Narlene's cabin looks abandoned
一直都这模样
That's how it always looks
是小棚子特有的时尚
It's shack chic
他们就在里面
They're in there
用我尾巴都能感觉得到
I can feel it in my tail
用你尾巴都能尝得到
I can taste it in your tail
烤派带了吗
You got your pie?
就放在我的烤派洞里呢
It's here, in my pie hole
等派大星吹竖笛吵醒他们
When Patrick wakes them up with the clarinet
就狠狠砸过去
let ‘em have it
为什么行不通
Why didn't that work?
假人
Dummies?
又是假人
More decoys?
派大星  帮帮忙
Patrick, help us
这就来
I got it
派大星
Patrick?
诺比  割下来
Nobby, cut ‘em down
这不是从前住小船小屋的笨蛋吗
If'n it ain't the old ding-dong Dinghies
来我们房子干什么
What y'all doing in our domicile?
别装傻了
Like you don't know
你们整晚都在恶搞我们
You've been pranking us all night
恐怕并没有
‘Fraid not
我们一直在忙着抓只小东西
We've been busy trying to catch a critter
它老是私闯我们家
that's been trespassing on our property
所以我们才安了这么个陷阱
That's why we rigged the booby trap
可惜陷阱到头来就只抓到过你们
Alas, the only boobies we caught t'were you
那小东西一定就是怪客
I bet it was the Creeper
他邀请我们参加团圆会
He invited us to a camp reunion
没想到把大家都抓走了
only to snatch everybody away
你们愿不愿意跟我们组队
How would you all like to team up with us
阻止这个大坏蛋
and put a stop to this varmint?
铁皮人怎么可能会让铁皮落单呢
Does the Tin Man have a sheet metal behind?
大家一起准备武器
Time we armed up
派大星  别吃武器
Patrick, don't eat your weapon
一起把怪客抓起来
Let's catch us a creeper
什么声音
What is that sound?
大家别怕
Don't worry, guys
我会用三明治保护你们的
I'll protect you with my sandwich
不要啊  我的三明治
Oh, no, my sandwich
谢了
Thanks
不会吧
Oh, no
那是派大星
That's Patrick
他被抓走了
He's been snatched
不管是什么  肯定都是来抓我们的
Whatever's out there is gonna get us
那就没得选了  只能
That leaves us only one option--
跑
Run
不对
No
我是想说反击
I was gonna say "fight back"
好嗨糖浆
Sugar Squeezin'
壮胆
For courage
还要再壮胆
Need more courage
怪客一定抓不到我
That Creeper will never catch me
我要躲进树桩地道系统里去了
in my underground tree stump system
我被抓到了
I'm caught
别过来
Stand back
我有电动榔头  而且还敢拿它砸你
I got an electro-hammer, and I'm not afraid to use it
我榔头失控了
My hammer's gone haywire
执行B计划
Time for plan B
再见了  怪客
So long, Creeper
现在知道变成气球是什么感觉了
Now I know what a balloon feels like
海贝大剧场
The Clampitheater?
你就在这里藏尸吗
Is that where you've been hiding all the bodies?
为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this?
因为
Because
很好玩啊
this is fun
阿伍
Elwood?
嗨  珊迪
Hi, Sandy
不知道你出了什么事
I always wondered what happened to you
都是好多年以前的事情了
It was all those years ago
我错过了珊瑚营回家的最后一趟大巴
I missed the last bus home from Kamp Koral
就在夏令营最后一天
on the last day of camp
从那以后  我就单独住在这里了
And I've been living here alone ever since
可好玩了
It's been fun
但我很想念你们
But I missed all you guys
然后某天我突发奇想
Then one day I thought
要是开个团圆会
if I throw a reunion
大家就都能重返珊瑚营地
everyone would come back to Kamp Koral
一起玩耍一辈子
and we could play forever
单独住了这么久
Living all by your lonesome
社交能力根本没法见长吧
didn't help your social skills none, did it?
没错
Nope
朋友都在这里
And here's all our friends
阿伍
Elwood?
这都是你干的吗
You did this?
你也可以一起来
And you can join them
还有一位客人没找来呢
I have one more guest to fetch
好了
There
叫了这么久  应该把怪客吓跑了
All that screaming should keep the Creeper away
我错了
I was wrong
还得再叫几下
I need more screaming
好
OK
真抱歉我先前背对着黑暗讲故事
I'm sorry I told a story with my back to the dark
但我真没亲亲抱抱  不管那什么意思
but I never canoodled, whatever that is
拜托别杀了我
Please don't kill me
我还年轻  不能死啊
I'm too young to die
还有不少蟹黄堡都还没做呢
I've got so many more Krabby Patties to make
我朋友都死了
My friends are all dead
原来没死
No, they're not
但都变成僵尸了
They're all zombies
我们才没变僵尸
We're not zombies
就只是等你等得无聊了
We got bored waiting for you
才打了番茄酱大战
so we had a ketchup fight
然后打累了
And then we got tired
就睡了
and took a nap
完全就是我会做的事情
That's exactly what I would have done
阿伍
Hey, Elwood
番茄酱用光了
We're out of ketchup
阿伍
Elwood?
你就是珊瑚营怪客吗
You're the Kamp Creeper?
是没错吧
I guess so
对
Yeah
刚刚那些全都是他的歪门邪道
All of this is his blundering way
单纯是邀请大家参加珊瑚营地团圆会
of inviting all of us to a Kamp Koral reunion
我一点社交能力都没有
I have no social skills
对
Yeah
那
So, uh
现在呢
what now?
那现在呢
So what now?
那就狂欢吧
So let's party
开始吧
Hit it
拖网渔船小屋
不要
No
欢迎回归
珊瑚营地
Kamp Koral
阿伍绑架了大家
Elwood kidnapped everyone
珊瑚营地
Kamp Koral
现在来开始狂欢
Now the party has begun
珊瑚营地
Kamp Koral
以为小命不保
We thought we'd be killed
结果却超嗨
Instead we're so thrilled
脚趾也痛快
Right down to our toes
派对不错啊  小子
Great party, lad
我跟你说
Listen, eh
想问一下
I was wondering
你什么时候要带我去找我失踪的财宝
when you were gonna show me where me lost treasure is
就这回事
You know
你眼前的就是
You're looking at it
都花在这派对上了
I spent it on this party
我寄的半毛零钱你不是都收到了吗
Didn't you get the nickel change I sent you?
更何况
And besides
千万别说
Don't say it
真正的财宝不就是朋友吗
Aren't friends the real treasure?
不要
No
深切怀念  美术总监  彼得·本内特